(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-27T21:09:47.797516",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
剥がれ落ちたメイク すっぴんのアニマル
The makeup peels off, a barefaced animal,
醜くてもやっちゃうのよ
I'll do it even if it's ugly!
おすわりとかできない だって待てもできない
I can't sit, and I can't stay either,
喉鳴らして いっちゃうまで
purring away until I lose it.
がぶっとしようよ 高まるビート
Let's bite right in, a rising beat.
良いも悪いも全部しよう
Let's experience both good and bad.
ハマってみようか 突破するゲート
Let's get hooked, breaking through the gate.
愛に期待は禁物だよ
High expectations of love are forbidden!
ねえ止まらないほどに狂いたい
Hey, I want to go crazy to the point of no stopping.
心真っ赤にしてどうしちゃったの？
My heart is bright red, what happened to me?
痛みすらもし愛せたら あたしは幸せです
If I could even love the pain, I'd be happy.
剥がれ落ちたメイク すっぴんのアニマル
The makeup peels off, a barefaced animal,
醜くてもやっちゃうのよ
I'll do it even if it's ugly!
おすわりとかできない だって待てもできない
I can't sit, and I can't stay either,
喉鳴らして いっちゃうまで
purring away until I lose it.
牙を出して叫べ ずっきゅんだ
Show your fangs and scream, Zukkyun!
あたしは噛み付いたら離さないにゃ
Once I bite down, I won't let go, meow!
剥がれ落ちたメイク すっぴんのアニマル
The makeup peels off, a barefaced animal,
醜くてもやっちゃうのよ
I'll do it even if it's ugly!
アガっちゃってよ クルっちゃってよ
Get hyped, go crazy,
メグっちゃってよ ンアッハッハ
get dizzy, n-hahaha!
アガっちゃってよ クルっちゃってよ
Get hyped, go crazy,
メグっちゃってよ ンアッハッハ
get dizzy, n-hahaha!
いやいやいや 噛み甲斐なくてつまらない
No no no, it's boring with no worth biting,
せめてちょっと拒んで欲しかったな
I wanted you to resist at least a little bit.
少しだけ欲張れるなら あたしは幸せに
If I can be just a little greedy, I want to be
なりたいです
happy.
剥がれ落ちたメイク すっぴんのアニマル
The makeup peels off, a barefaced animal,
醜くてもやっちゃうのよ
I'll do it even if it's ugly!
おすわりとかできない だって待てもできない
I can't sit, and I can't stay either,
喉鳴らして いっちゃうまで
purring away until I lose it.
塗り重ねたメイク ばっちりなアニマル
Layered makeup, a perfect animal,
目を開いて待ってるのよ
I'm waiting with my eyes wide open.
おすわりとかできない だって待てもできない
I can't sit, and I can't stay either,
喉鳴らして いっちゃうまで
purring away until I lose it.
牙を出して叫べ ずっきゅんだ
Show your fangs and scream, Zukkyun!
あたしは噛み付いたら離さないにゃ
Once I bite down, I won't let go, meow!
塗り重ねたメイク ばっちりなアニマル
Layered makeup, a perfect animal,
目を開いて待ってるのよ
I'm waiting with my eyes wide open.
にゃお うにゃお しゃしゃしゃしゃしゃ
Meow, umeow, shashashasha!
お願いマッスル めっちゃモテたい
Onegai Muscle, I want to be super popular!
お願いマッスル めっちゃ痩せたい YES!
Onegai Muscle, I want to get super lean, YES!
お願いマッスル めっちゃモテたいから
Onegai Muscle, because I want to be super popular,
(キレてるよ！)
(You're ripped!)
筋肉にお願い！
Asking the muscles!
ヒップレイズ！ サイドベンド！
Hip raise! Side bend!
(腹筋6LDKかい!!)
(Abs like a 6LDK apartment!)
ダンベルカール！ ハンマーカール！
Dumbbell curl! Hammer curl!
(二頭筋いいね！チョモランマ！)
(Great biceps! Mount Everest!)
プッシュアップ！ ベンチプレス！
Push up! Bench press!
(大胸筋歩いてる！)
(Your pectorals are walking!)
仕上がってるよ！仕上がってるよ！
You're in peak shape! You're in peak shape!
筋肉本舗はいズドーン！
Muscle Hompo is boom!
理想の自分を思い描いたら今すぐ始めようトレーニング！ (イエス、マッスル！)
If you envision your ideal self, start training right now! (Yes, Muscle!)
ダンベル両手にフリーウェイト！ (ポーズマッチョ！)
Dumbbells in both hands for free weights! (Pose, macho!)
焦りは禁物無理しちゃ沈没負荷のかけ方調節 (そう、筋肉！)
Haste makes waste, overdoing it sinks you. (Right, muscles!)
限界10回ギリギリ全開！3セットしたらオーライ！ (ナイスポーズ！)
10 reps to failure, pushing to the limit! Do 3 sets! (Nice pose!)
辛いこともある筋肉道 (筋肉道)
The path of muscle has its hardships (The path of muscle)
モテモテボディが欲しいの (欲しいの)
You want a super popular body? (You want it?)
綺麗なワタシに大変身 (大変身)
Transform into a gorgeous me! (Big transformation)
さあ！はい、サイドチェストーーー！
Come on! Yes, side chest!
お願いマッスル めっちゃモテたい
Onegai Muscle, I want to be super popular,
お願いマッスル めっちゃ痩せたい YES!
Onegai Muscle, I want to get super lean, YES!
お願いマッスル めっちゃモテたいから
Onegai Muscle, because I want to be super popular,
(キレてるよ！)
(You're ripped!)
筋肉にお願い！
Asking the muscles!
レッグカール！バックリフト！ (泣く子も黙る大腿筋！)
Leg curl! Back lift! (Quadriceps that'll quiet crying children!)
バックプレス！サイドレイズ！ (肩にちっちゃい重機のせてんのかい!!)
Back press! Side raise! (Carrying a tiny heavy machine on your shoulder?!)
ベントオーバー！ラットプルダウン！ (背中に鬼神が宿ってる！)
Bent-over row! Lat pulldown! (A demon god dwells in your back!)
仕上がってるよ！仕上がってるよ！
You're in peak shape! You're in peak shape!
頑張るあなたは美しい！
You doing your best are beautiful!
昨日の今日では効果出なくてもとにかく続けよトレーニング！ (超マッスル！)
Even if today shows no results, keep training anyway! (Super muscle!)
気分を変えたいコンビネーションで辛いそれならマシンでワン・カ・セ (見て！筋肉！)
If combinations are too tough, use machines! (Look! Muscles!)
食べて食べるの大切 筋肉の秘訣食事で体を建設！ (ボディビルディング！)
Eating is important, build your body with food! (Bodybuilding!)
週に1回に2～3回無理ないペースでオッケー！ (ナイスバルク！)
2 to 3 times a week is fine at a comfortable pace! (Nice bulk!)
めげそうな時を思い出して努力が身に付けば魅惑 (思い出して)
Remember those times, if effort becomes part of you, it's fascinating
見せつけたいでしょ脚線美 頑張ります！ (脚線美 / 頑張ります)
You want to show off your beautiful leg lines, I'll do my best!
はい、モストマスキュラーーー！
Yes, most muscular!
お願いマッスル めっちゃモテたい
Onegai Muscle, I want to be super popular,
お願いマッスル めっちゃ痩せたい YES!
Onegai Muscle, I want to get super lean, YES!
お願いマッスル めっちゃモテたいから
Onegai Muscle, because I want to be super popular,
(キレてるよ！)
(You're ripped!)
筋肉にお願い！
Asking the muscles!
いくよ！今から私とトレーニング！
Here we go! Train with me right now!
足を肩幅分開いたら両手は頭の後ろにあげて片足を軽くあげたら準備はオッケー！
Open your feet shoulder-width, put hands behind your head, and lift one leg. Ready? OK!
It's ステップポジション！上げた足と逆の肘をくっつけるように腹筋を収縮！収縮！収縮！収縮！
It's step position! Contract abs so opposite elbow touches! Contract!
できたら戻して逆側も！足と足と逆の肘をくっつけるように腹筋を収縮！収縮！収縮！収縮！
Return and do the other side! Contract abs so opposite elbow touches! Contract!
できたら戻してもう1回！足と足と逆の肘をくっつけるように腹筋を収縮！収縮！収縮！収縮！
Do it one more time! Contract abs so opposite elbow touches! Contract!
筋肉に！筋肉にお願いだ！はい、サイドチェストー！
To the muscles! Ask the muscles! Yes, side chest!
お願いマッスル めっちゃモテたい
Onegai Muscle, I want to be super popular,
お願いマッスル めっちゃ痩せたい YES!
Onegai Muscle, I want to get super lean, YES!
お願いマッスル めっちゃモテたいから
Onegai Muscle, because I want to be super popular,
(キレてるよ！)
(You're ripped!)
筋肉にお願い！
Asking the muscles!
ヒップレイズ！サイドベンド！(腹筋板チョコ！バレンタイン！)
Hip raise! Side bend! (Chocolate bar abs! Valentine!)
ダンベルカール！ハンマーカール！ (これが二頭の新時代…！)
Dumbbell curl! Hammer curl! (This is the new era of biceps...!)
プッシュアップ！ベンチプレス！
Push up! Bench press!
(ちぎれそうな大胸筋！)
(Pectorals on the verge of tearing!)
サイドクランチ！ハイクリーン！(出たなプロポーションおばけ！)
Side crunch! High clean! (There's the proportion monster!)
レッグカール！ハックリフト！ (ザッツ奥深い大腿筋！)
Leg curl! Hack lift! (Deeply profound quadriceps!)
バックプレス！サイドレイズ！ (これがで新鮮肩メロン！)
Back press! Side raise! (Fresh shoulder melons!)
ベントオーバー！ラットプルダウン！ (背中に世界を背負ってる！)
Bent-over row! Lat pulldown! (Carrying the world on your back!)
仕上がってるよ！仕上がってるよ！
You're in peak shape! You're in peak shape!
頑張るあなたは美しい！
You doing your best are beautiful!
お願いマッスル
Onegai Muscle
らっしゃいな 平は成り
Welcome, peace is established
時が来た 正しい夢現 夜もすがら
The time has come, a true dreamlike reality through the night
変わりゆくことに恐れなし
Having no fear of changing things
のっぴきならないのは御免
Being cornered is out of the question
手弱女歌い 君達が誘う
Singing maiden songs, you invite us
悪人に後ろ髪引かれても 進むべきなり
Even if held back by evildoers, we must press forward
流行り廃りの憂き世ならずば 信ずる者はただ、君だけと
If not for this fleeting world, the only one I believe in is you
踊れ騒げや 呑みや歌えや 案ずることなどないな
Dance and make noise, drink and sing, there's nothing to worry about
Oh my god
愛のネタバレ「別れ」っぽいな
Spilling love's secrets, so like a "breakup"
人生のネタバレ「死ぬ」っぽいな
Spilling life's secrets, so like "death"
なにそれ意味深でかっこいいじゃん…
What's with that? It's profound and cool...
それっぽい単語集で踊ってんだ
Dancing to a collection of buzzwords
失敬
Pardon me
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる “風”
Tu-turu-tu-tu-turu "fuu"
っぽいじゃん っぽいじゃん
Sort of like it, sort of like it
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる “風”
Tu-turu-tu-tu-turu "fuu"
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる
Tu-turu-tu-tu-turu
神っぽいな
That's god-ish
あまりに精神とがった悲劇
A tragedy with an overly sharp spirit,
身勝手なのが世の理なのそのことわりか？
selfish ways being the logic of the world...
万人理想 虚像 偶像
Universal ideals, virtual images, idols,
鬱陶しいと
feeling they're annoying.
俗な答えなのは だちゃかん
Vulgar answers are just no good.
僕ら巡り会うこと まさに一期一会
For us to cross paths is truly a once-in-a-lifetime meeting.
酸いも甘いも試練 連れ添ってこの手握って
Through both bitter and sweet trials, holding hands side by side.
生きづらい此処、浮世世から退屈凌ぎを繰り
In this hard-to-live floating world, passing time with boredom-busting.
旗を掲げよ 宵闇明く
Raise the banner, dawn breaks through the twilight.
酔い痴れやがれ 眠れは忘るる
Get intoxicated and revel, sleep makes you forget.
昔も今も変わらず 浮世人の世嘆かわしい
Unchanged from past to present, the lamentable world of floating people.
いつだってちゃんちゃらおかしい
Always utterly ridiculous.
荒んで笑って合縁奇縁 それそれそれそれ
Laughing through desolation, fateful bonds, step by step!
深まる春も凍てつく雪の日も
In deepening spring or freezing snowy days,
日出ずるすべての瞬きを君と見よう
let's witness every single sunrise blink together with you.
彩る色 何処までも 空前なる見晴らしを眺めて
Vibrant colors anywhere, gazing at an unprecedented vista.
負けて花一匁
Losing at flower-picking,
欲しがる欲しがる欲しがる声
voices that keep craving and wanting.
買って買って買って買って勝手になって
Buying, getting, buying, getting, acting selfishly.
猿真似の何番煎じ道中満ち足りないのよ
Countless rehashes of monkey see, monkey do, never feeling fulfilled.
あいあっそー
Aii-assou...
愛なんてさ、その道の中
Love, on that path,
あいあっそー
Aii-assou...
如何なる時も歩みを前へ出せ
No matter when, keep your steps moving forward.
流行り廃りの憂き世なら 宵闇よさらば
If it's a fickle, transient world, farewell to the twilight.
信じる者はただ、君だけと
The only one who believes is you alone.
踊れ騒げや 呑めや歌えや 案ずる事など何もない
Dance and make noise, drink and sing, there's nothing to worry about.
此の世人の世は恨めしい
This mortal world is resentful,
雪駄はちゃらちゃら愛し
clacking geta shoes, so dear.
縫って眩んで満身創痍で 酔いで騒げ騒げ騒げ
Sewn together, dazzled, covered in wounds, get drunk and make noise!
今を嘆いて昔を懐かしても
Even if we lament the present and yearn for the past,
君の心は流る涙川
your heart is a flowing river of tears.
空の女からまあ どこにいてもめくるめく
From the sky woman, wherever you are, spinning around...
舞台は宵々、君を連れて
the stage is twilight, taking you along.
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる “風”
Tu-turu-tu-tu-turu "fuu"
っぽいじゃん っぽいじゃん
Sort of like it, sort of like it
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる “風”
Tu-turu-tu-tu-turu "fuu"
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる
Tu-turu-tu-tu-turu
神っぽいな
That's god-ish
あまりに精神とがった悲劇
A tragedy with an overly sharp spirit,
身勝手なのが世の理なの
selfish ways being the logic of the world...
移ろうは古今 航路水と堂々
Shifting from past to present, grandly navigating the waterway.
恐るることはあざ笑う
Laughing scornfully at anything to be feared.
へい、ここかなた！2022年4月22日、あまねかなたバースデーライブ、バーチャルアイドルが踊ってみた始まりましたー！イェーイ！
Hey everyone! April 22, 2022, Amane Kanata Birthday Live has started! Yay!
えー今回アニマルお願いまする。そしてよよいここんをお聴きいただきましたー！みんなどうだったー？イェーイ！
And you heard "Yoyoikokon"! How was it, everyone? Yay!
え、ありがとう！コメント盛り上がってくれてありがとう！え、今回のライブのコンセプトはズバリ、「ダンスアイドルかなた」となっております！
Thank you for getting so hyped in the comments! The concept of this live is precisely "Dance Idol Kanata"!
12月の「リベンジ」というライブとはまた違ったかなたをお届けするので、いっぱい楽しんでいってね！
We're delivering a Kanata different from the December "Revenge" live, so please enjoy it to the fullest!
そしてみんな今日の合言葉は、「かなたしか勝たん」！いっぱいつぶやいてね！
And everyone, today's catchphrase is "Kanata shika katan"! Tweet it a lot!
それでは早速次の曲、ちょっとクールなあの曲をあのこと一緒に歌って踊ります！それでは、ミュージック、スタート！
Now, for the next song, we'll sing and dance to a cool song with that girl! Music, start!
愛のネタバレ「別れ」っぽいな
Spilling love's secrets, so like a "breakup"
人生のネタバレ「死ぬ」っぽいな
Spilling life's secrets, so like "death"
なにそれ意味深でかっこいいじゃん…
What's with that? It's profound and cool...
それっぽい単語集で踊ってんだ
Dancing to a collection of buzzwords
失敬
Pardon me
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる “風”
Tu-turu-tu-tu-turu "fuu"
っぽいじゃん っぽいじゃん
Sort of like it, sort of like it
とぅ とぅるる とぅ とぅるる とぅ とぅるる "風"
Tu tururu tu tururu tu tururu "wind"
神っぽいな
God-ish
もういいぜ もういいぜ それ もういいぜ もういいぜ 逆に興奮してきたなあ
Enough already, yeah... I'm getting kind of excited.
おっきいね おっきいね 夢 おっきいね おっきいね 景気いいけど 品性はTHE END
Huge dreams, so huge! Business is booming, but class is at THE END.
うぇえい うぇえい "Gott ist tot"
Yay, yay! "Gott ist tot"
神っぽいな それ 卑怯 神っぽいな それ
God-ish, yeah, how cowardly. God-ish, yeah.
アイウォンチュー ウォンチュー IQが下がっていく感じ
I want you, want you, feeling my IQ drop.
邪心っぽいな それ 卑怯 邪心っぽいな それ
Wicked-ish, yeah, how cowardly. Wicked-ish, yeah.
アイヘイチュー ヘイチュー ヘイチューはルチ
I hate you, hate you, hate you are the worst.
その髪型 その目 その口元 その香水 その服 そのメイク アレっぽいな それ 比況 アレっぽいな それ
That hairstyle, those eyes, that mouth... That perfume, that outfit, that makeup... That-ish, yeah, how cowardly. That-ish, yeah.
その名言 その意見 その批評 そのカリスマ そのギャグ そのセンス
Those famous quotes, opinions, and critiques... That charisma, that gag, that sense...
神っぽいな それ 卑怯 ぽいな ぽいな ぽい 憧れちゃう!
God-ish, yeah, how cowardly. -ish, -ish, -ish, I adore it!
とぅ とぅるる とぅ とぅるる とぅ とぅるる "風"
Tu tururu tu tururu tu tururu "wind"
っぽいじゃん っぽいじゃん
That's so-ish, that's so-ish!
とぅ とぅるる とぅ とぅるる とぅ とぅるる "風" 神っぽいな
Tu tururu tu tururu tu tururu "wind"... God-ish.
メタ思考する本質は悪意? 人を小馬鹿にしたような作意
Is the essence of meta-thinking malice? Intended to make a fool of people.
無為に生き延びるのは難しい 権力に飲まれて揺らぐ灯り
Surviving aimlessly is hard. A flicker swallowed by power.
神を否定し神に成り代わり 玉座で豹変する小物達
Denying God and taking His place, small fries transforming on the throne.
批判に見せかけ自戒の祈り Do you know?
Posing as criticism, a prayer of self-reproach. Do you know?
何言ってんの? それ ウザい 何言ってんの? それ
What are you saying? So annoying. What are you saying?
意味がよくわかんないし 眠っちゃうよ マジ
I don't really get it, I'm gonna fall asleep, seriously.
飽きっぽいんだ オーケー みんな 飽きっぽいんだ オーケー
Easily bored, okay? Everyone gets bored easily, okay?
踊れるやつ ちょうだい ちょうだい ビーム
Give me something we can dance to! Give me, give me the beam!
きっしょいね きっしょいね それきっしょいね きっしょいね 逆にファンになってきたんじゃん
Creepy, creepy, yeah, creepy, creepy... You've actually become a fan, haven't you?
ちっちゃいね ちっちゃいねっつうかちっちゃいね ちっちゃいね 天才ゆえ孤独ですね かっけ… かっけ…
Tiny, tiny, I mean tiny, tiny... Lonely because you're a genius. So cool... so cool...
"Gott ist tot" 神っぽいな それ 卑怯 神っぽいな それ "My God"
"Gott ist tot" / God-ish, yeah, how cowardly. God-ish, yeah, "My God".
超健康 健康 言い張って くたばっていく感じ
Insisting you're super healthy, running yourself down.
ヤケっぽいな それ 卑怯 ヤケっぽいな それ "My God"
Desperate-ish, yeah, how cowardly. Desperate-ish, yeah, "My God".
もう哀愁 哀愁 エビゴーネンのヒール
More melancholy, melancholy, Everygonin's heels.
そのタイトル その絵 そのストーリー その音楽 その歌 そのメロディ
That title, that art, that story... That music, that song, that melody...
アレっぽいな それ 卑怯 アレっぽいな それ
That-ish, yeah, how cowardly. That-ish, yeah.
その名言 その意見 その批評 そのカリスマ そのギャグ そのセンス
Those famous quotes, opinions, and critiques... That charisma, that gag, that sense...
神っぽいな それ 卑怯 ぽいな ぽいな ぽい 憧れちゃう!
God-ish, yeah, how cowardly. -ish, -ish, -ish, I adore it!
とぅ とぅるる とぅ とぅるる とぅ とぅるる "風" っぽいじゃん っぽいじゃん
Tu tururu tu tururu tu tururu "wind"... That's so-ish, that's so-ish!
とぅ とぅるる とぅ とぅるる とぅ とぅるる "風" 神っぽいな
Tu tururu tu tururu tu tururu "wind"... God-ish.
愛のネタバレ 「別れ」っぽいな
Spoiler alert for love, it looks like a "breakup".
人生のネタバレ 「死ぬ」っぽいな
Spoiler alert for life, it looks like "death".
すべて理解して患った 無邪気に踊っていたかった 人生
Understanding everything and falling ill... I wish I could've danced innocently, my life.
エビバディ→解体！思い出に消しゴム！？あれっ。 ハイになる？廃になる？ はい、とは言えな~い!!!!
Everybody → disassembly! Erasing memories with a rubber!? Huh? Getting high? Becoming ruined? Yes, I can't say that!!!!
お可愛い世界 お菓子は消えちゃう!?どうしよ どうしても!!あーしても!!君らしくないな?
Such a cute world, will the sweets disappear!? What should I do? No matter how I do it, it's not like you?
そんな時代でいいよ 僕らまだまだ信じてるの No? know!
That kind of era is fine, we still believe in it, right? No? know!
おとなたちの鋭利な目盛り 悩ませすぎちゃって 寄り目になっちゃいそーね!!
Adults' sharp gauges, worrying too much till I'm going cross-eyed!!
どうして!?“あーして!!”も「全部」だいすき!がいいじゃん!! みんなみんな笑っちゃえの魂胆で
Why!? Even with "do this," "I love everything!" is better, right!? With the plot to make everyone laugh!
宿敵 逆境モンスター呼んだっていいじゃん!? スットンキョウでサイキョウなセカイを
It's fine to call an arch-nemesis adversity monster!? A quirky and strongest world!
どうにもこうにも救えない困難もいいじゃん!! みんなみんな救っちゃおのポーズで
Troubles that can't be saved no matter what are fine too!! With the pose of saving everyone!
ちょっとやそっとじゃ潰れない笑顔でいちゃん! 100回オチても不思議は鳥壊せない!
With a smile that won't break easily! Even if the punchline fails 100 times, the mystery won't break!
ワンワンでツーカーでスリーフォー エビバディ ショウタイム!
One-two, two-car, three-four, everybody showtime!
セカイ解体10秒前!?待って待って待って
10 seconds before world disassembly!? Wait, wait, wait!
まだまだ一緒にしよなの魂胆です
It's still our plan to be together more!
101回目のそんなメモリー敗者 ハッピーも失敗も消せないから!
That 101st memory loser, because neither happiness nor failure can be erased!
セカイ ウチュウ 未来 超だいすきでキューじゃん! みんなみんな笑っちゃえの正解は
World, universe, future, super loved and cue! The correct answer for everyone laughing together is...
宿敵 逆境モンスター呼んだっていいじゃん!? スットンキョウでサイキョウ お菓子いざろ?
It's fine to call an arch-nemesis adversity monster!? A quirky and strongest sweet adventure, right?
旋回 満開 もう1回だいすきでキューじゃん! みんなみんなクソぐっちゃえのポーズで
Revolving, full bloom, once again super loved and cue! With everyone's chaotic mixed pose!
ぜったいぜったいね、消せない笑顔でいちゃん! 100回オチても不思議は鳥壊せない!
Definitely, definitely, with an unerasable smile! Even if the punchline fails 100 times, the wonder won't be broken!
ワンワンでツーカーでスリーフォー エビバディ ショウタイム!
One-two, two-car, three-four, everybody showtime!
やばい 止まれない 止まらない
Crap, I can't stop, won't stop
昼に夜に朝に singing so loud
Morning, noon and night I'm singing so loud
好きなことしてるだけだよ Girls Go Maniac
We only know the things we like, us girls go maniac
あんなメロディ こんなリリック
That kind of melody, these kinds of lyrics
探していきたいんだ もっともっと
We wanna search for 'em more and more
みんな一緒にね Chance Chance 願いを
Everyone, together, take a chance chance, your wishes,
Jump Jump 掲げて
Jump jump, raise 'em up,
Fun Fun 想いを Shout Shout 伝えよう
Have some fun fun, your feelings, shout shout 'em out, express 'em
ミスったらリハってことにして、もっかい！
If you mess up, rehearse it and do it one more time!
K-A-N-A-T-A!
誰をもってるハートっていう名の小宇宙
Everyone has a tiny world in them called \"the heart\"
ギュッと詰まっているよ 喜怒哀楽や愛
Packed tightly with emotions and love
シュンっとなったり ワクワクしたり busy
Busy feeling down, getting excited
カオス満載な日々 歌いにしちゃおう
I'll sing about these days loaded with chaos
ぶつけ合っちゃおう
Let's clash them together!
授業中も無意識に 研究する musicianship
Even in class I'm unconsciously studying musicianship
エアでOK 雰囲気大事
Air guitar is ok, the feeling's what's important,
不意に刻むリズム
suddenly break out a rhythm
通じ合っちゃうビート マインド 自由エンジョイ 楽しんだもんが勝ち
I freely enjoy jamming out the beat in my mind, fun things are my victory!
ごめん ゆずるない ゆずるない
Sorry, I can't give in, won't give in
縦・横・斜め swinging around
Swinging around vertically, horizontally, diagonally
好きな音出してるだけだよ Girls Go Maniac
We only put out the sounds we like, so us girls go maniac
あんなグルーヴ こんなリバーヴ
That kind of groove, this kind of reverb
試していきたいんだ ずっとずっと
We wanna try 'em always, always
息合わせてね Chase Chase 明日を
With joint breaths, chase chasing tomorrow
Break Break 夢見て
Break break, dream of it
Faith Faith 強気で Shake Shake 盛り上がろう
Have some faith faith, swell up and shake shake with pride
浴びたら忘れらんないしょ、喝破！
If we're showered in praise, we'll never forget it!
ほんと現実にまじ奇なり 小説より
In reality, truth is stranger than fiction
ボケっとしててもね ぶつかる出会い
Though I space out, we run into each other and meet
キュンってなったり グッときたり funny
Its funny how my heart throbs and races
何これって運命？じゃ溺れちゃおう めい一杯堪能しちゃおう
What is this, fate? Then let's indulge in it and enjoy it to the fullest!
試験前も通常通り 引き裂けない friendship
Even before a test, we can't break from our friendship, as usual
約束してないのに つい集まる放課後
We get together after school without even planning to
どこだってメンバー揃った場所 即ステージ
No matter where we are, when all the members are together, it's an instant stage
聞こえるね？カウント
Can you hear it? The count off!
当然 笑顔でしょ 笑顔でね
Naturally, cuz we're smiling, with a smile
春も夏も秋も stepping out, now 好きな仲間といるだけだよ Girls Go Maniac
Spring, summer, or fall, stepping out, now, with the people we love, us girls go maniac
あんなドラミング こんなカッティング
That drumming, this palm muting
受け止めて欲しいんだ どうかどうか
I want you to get it, somehow, somehow
目合わせてね Tune Tune ココロも
Look me in the eye and tune tune, your heart
Amuse Amuse 重ねて
And add some amusement, amusement
Loose Loose 気楽に Shoot Shoot 技磨こう
Just let loose loose, and shoot shoot, to polish our techniques
まだまだいけるはずでしょ、実際！
We can still go on, right? Totally!
大人たちは言うけど 好きなことばっかじゃダメになるって言うけど
All the adults say it, all the things we love lead nowhere, but really!? How??
どうかな？どうかな？？
Could that be? Really!?
ねぇ 好きなことに夢中になってる瞬間ってさ
But ya know, when i'm in the moment, absorbed with doing these things
生きてるって感じだし…幸せだし…だからいいいや。
I feel like i'm really living... I'm happy... So there.
つーかダメになるわけないっ！
Sooooo, there's no reason to say it won't do us any good!
やっぱし 止まれない 止まらない
Crap, I can't stop, won't stop
昼に夜に朝に singing so loud
Morning, noon and night I'm singing so loud
好きなことしてるだけだよ Girls Go Maniac
We only know the things we like, us girls go maniac
あんなメロディ こんなリリック
That kind of melody, these kinds of lyrics
探していきたいんだ もっともっと
We wanna search for 'em more and more
みんな一緒にね Chance Chance 願いを
Everyone, together, take a chance chance, your wishes,
Jump Jump 掲げて
Jump jump, raise 'em up,
Fun Fun 想いを Shout Shout more
Have some fun fun, your feelings, shout shout 'em out some more
Chance Chance 願いを Jump Jump 掲げて
Take a chance chance, your wishes, jump jump, raise 'em up,
Fun Fun 想いを Shout Shout 伝えよう
Have some fun fun, your feelings, shout shout 'em out, express 'em
気持ちいいから Yeah アンコール、モッカイ！
We're feeling good so, yeah, encore! One more time!
Oh My God! No No music, No smile
Oh My God! No No friends, No life
All Right! No No No stop going our way
We have a fabulous body, soul & love
Oh My God! No No music, No smile
Oh My God! No No friends, No life
All Right! No No No stop going our way
We have a fabulous body, soul & love
Oh My God! No No music, No smile
Oh My God! No No friends, No life
All Right! No No No stop going our way
We have a fabulous body, soul & love
Oh My God! No No music, No smile
Oh My God! No No friends, No life
All Right! No No No stop going our way
We have a fabulous body, soul & love
幾つの苦も美親義
Countless hardships and aestheticism,
愛の反戦 一人じゃんけん
Anti-war of love, playing rock-paper-scissors alone,
運命と縛り無い振り
Faking no bounds with destiny,
それも暗転
Even that is just a plot twist.
now i know all about you babe
I don't want the handbags the money or the diamond rings
'Cause guys like you they all don't care about the little things
まあ Anyway 吹き切れた訳で
Well anyway, I've moved past it,
棒に当たって吠えたって圏外です
barking up the wrong tree is out of bounds.
I'm moving on and I'm never ever turning back around, around, around again
Now I'll go higher and I'll go higher
And you couldn't take me down if you tried
ばら撒いてた愛取り返し撤退だ
Taking back the love I scattered everywhere, it's a retreat.
Now I can finally open my eyes
そんで来世もっかい君への返品サイン
and in my next life, I'll return you once again.
Getcha out my life boy I'll getcha, getcha, getcha!
待ちっぱなしの恋なんて 錠をかけキー捨て去って
For a love that kept me waiting, lock it up and throw away the key.
'Cause I'm fine, I'm alright 君なしで大正解
'Cause I'm fine, I'm alright, being without you is absolute perfection.
Getcha out my life boy I'll getcha, getcha, getcha!
(Getcha out my life boy, get out of my life)
(Getcha out my life, boy, get out of my life, boy)
Oops! Deleted your number
All of my friends used to warn me about ya
Baby, I thought that I couldn't without ya
I got myself now I don't need no other (Ah yeah)
もう息も止まる時めきすらない今 酸素吸ってはいいちょ泳いでくか like na nana na na
Right now, not even a heartbeat that stops my breath, inhaling oxygen, shall I swim along like la-la-la-la?
I don't want the handbags the money or the diamond rings
'Cause guys like you they all don't care about the little things
そう Everyday 自己愛は順調で 先手打ち勝ち賞金掠めて bye babe
Yes everyday, self-love is going smoothly, striking first to win and snatching the prize, bye babe.
I'm moving on and I'm never ever turning back around, around, around again
Now I'll go higher and I'll go higher
And you couldn't take me down if you tried
ばら撒いてた愛取り返し撤退だ
Taking back the love I scattered everywhere, it's a retreat.
Now I can finally open my eyes
今までにない待ちわびた最終回
An unprecedented, long-awaited final episode.
Getcha out my life boy I'll getcha, getcha, getcha!
All the lies and every mistake All the goodbyes and the heartbreak
枯れ切った涙さえ No more
Even dried-up tears, no more...
Break!!
(It's Giga and KIRA)
You ready?
(Getcha out my life boy, getcha out my life boy)
囮ってた偽造ID 暴落した価値 four on knees
Hiding a forged ID, plummeting values, four on knees.
円滑な生活reigns 流されてくスライダー outta way
Smooth living reigns, swept away like a slider outta way.
盲目な愛が溶けくアイスバー もろく砕け泡が抜けたソーダ
Blind love melting like an ice bar, brittle, crumbling, losing its fizz like soda.
からってNo pressure not to press ya I'll getcha
No pressure, not to press ya, I'll getcha.
ばら撒いてた愛取り返し撤退だ
Taking back the love I scattered everywhere, it's a retreat.
Now I can finally open my eyes
そんで来世もっかい君への返品サイン
and in my next life, I'll return you once again.
Getcha out my life boy I'll getcha, getcha, getcha!
待ちっぱなしの恋なんて 錠をかけキー捨て去って
For a love that kept me waiting, lock it up and throw away the key.
今までにない待ちわびた最終回
An unprecedented, long-awaited final episode.
Getcha out my life boy I'll getcha, getcha, getcha!
'Cause I'm fine, I'm alright 君なしで大正解
'Cause I'm fine, I'm alright, being without you is absolute perfection.
Getcha out my life boy I'll getcha, getcha, getcha!
イェーイ！
Yay!
お送りしたのはアクタンと神っぽいな。
The song we just sent you was "God-ish" with Aqua-tan.
その次にあきろぜ先輩、メルメル先輩、すばる先輩、ねねちゃんと、とんでもワンダーズと、GOGOマニアック！そしてそして新しい挑戦、もう一人のカナタとGETCHAでした！
And after that, with Akirose-senpai, Mel-senpai, Subaru-senpai, and Nene-chan, "Tongemo Wonders" and "Go! Go! Maniac!", and then a new challenge with another Kanata, "GETCHA!"!
アクタンとの神っぽいなはね、歌ってみた動画が上がってるんですけど、ぜひ一緒に踊りたいと思って今回声かけました。アクタンありがとう！
For "God-ish" with Aqua-tan, a cover video is already out, but I asked her because I wanted to dance together. Thank you, Aqua-tan!
そしてとんでもワンダーズ、こちらはプロセカ世界の曲とダンスをやらさせていただきました。プロセカ指がちぎれるけど最高です。
And "Tongemo Wonders," we got to perform the song and dance from the Sekai world in Project SEKAI. Project SEKAI makes your fingers tear off, but it's the best!
え、今回のライブをやるにあたって、あのフォーメンショがあって難しいダンスを踊ってみたいなってなったときに思い浮かんだのがね、あの4人だったんですが、みんな心良く参加してくれました。え、本当になんかめちゃめちゃ難しい振り付けだったけど、一緒に頑張ってくれて嬉しかったです。
Um, when planning this live, I thought about wanting to dance a difficult dance with a formation, and those four came to mind, and they all willingly participated. Um, it was honestly such a difficult choreography, but I was so happy they worked hard together with me.
そして、え、GOGOマニアックは一夜限りのエアバンドを組ませていただきました。「かなたん」という強めの承認欲求が考えられるユニット名になってしまいましたが、そのせいで先ほど解散しました。
And, um, "Go! Go! Maniac" was a one-night-only air band. It ended up being a unit name where you can think of the strong approval desire called "Kanatan," and because of that, we just disbanded.
今回のね、ライブの演出は僕自身が提案・監督しているんですけども、
For this live concert, I actually proposed and directed the staging myself,
ホロライブのすごい技術により、どれも素敵に実現していただきました。
and with Hololive's amazing technology, they've all been wonderfully brought to life.
記者と言えば、カリオペちゃんスレイちゃんのが歌ってみたのイメージがみんなあると思うけど、英語をね1人で頑張りましたが
Speaking of reporters, I think everyone has the image of Calliope-chan and Suisei-chan's covers, but I did my best with English all by myself,
どうだったかな？海外ニキ！
how was it? Overseas bros!
はーいハニー！どうですか？どうだった？
Hii, honey! How is it? How was it?
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
さて、ではそろそろ次の曲、ここからの3曲はしっとりめの曲となっております。
Now then, it's almost time for the next song. The next three songs from here are emotional tracks.
それではまずこちらから聞いてください、「One Last Kiss」。
Well then, first, please listen to this: "One Last Kiss".
One Last Kiss
[Title: One Last Kiss]
初めてのルーブルは
My first time at the Louvre
なんてことはなかったわ 私だけのモナリザ
was no big deal—my very own Mona Lisa
もっととくに出会ってたから
had been met long, long ago.
初めてあなたを見た あの日動き出した歯車 止められない喪失の予感
The day I first saw you, the gears started turning—an unstoppable premonition of loss.
もういっぱいあるけど
We already have so many,
もう一つ増やしましょう
but let's add one more.
Can you give me one last kiss?
忘れたくないこと
Something I don't want to forget
Oh oh oh oh oh…
忘れたくないこと
Something I don't want to forget
Oh oh oh oh oh… I love you more than you’ll ever know
「写真は苦手なんだ」 でもそんなものはいらないわ
"I'm not good at photos," but I don't need such things.
あなたが焼き付いたまま 私の心のプロジェクター
Your image burnt into my heart's projector screen.
寂しくないふりしてた まぁそんなのお互い様か
I was pretending I wasn't lonely—well, I guess that makes two of us.
誰かを求めることは 即ち傷つくことだった
Yearning for someone came hand in hand with heartache.
Oh, can you give me one last kiss?
燃えるようなキスをしよう
A kiss as hot as fire—
忘れたくても 忘れられないほど Oh oh oh oh oh…
so passionately that even if I wanted to, I won't be able to forget it. Oh oh oh oh oh…
I love you more than you’ll ever know Oh oh oh oh oh…
もう分かっているよ この世の終わりでも
I already know, whether it's the end of the world
年をとっても 忘られない人
or I grow to be old, the one I won't be able to forget.
忘られない人 Oh oh oh oh oh…
The one I can't forget Oh oh oh oh oh…
I love you more than you’ll ever know Oh oh oh oh oh…
吹いていった風の後を 追いかけた 眩しい午後
Chasing after the breeze that blew by one dazzling afternoon.
Beautiful world
もしも願い一つだけ叶うなら
If I am granted only one wish,
君の側で眠らせて
let me sleep by your side,
どんな場所でもいいよ
anywhere is fine.
Beautiful world
もしも願い一つだけ叶うなら
If I am granted only one wish,
君の側で眠らせて
let me sleep by your side,
どんな場所でもいいよ
anywhere is fine.
Beautiful world
迷わず君だけを見つめている
I am looking only at you without hesitation.
Beautiful boy
自分の美しさまだ知らないの
You still don't know your own beauty.
It's only love
寝ても覚めても少年マンガ
Whether asleep or awake, boy's manga
夢見てばっか自分が好きじゃないの
I just keep dreaming, I don't like myself.
何が欲しいか分からなくて
Not knowing what I want,
ただ欲しがってぬるい涙が頬を伝う
just wanting it, tepid tears run down my cheeks.
言いたいことなんか無いただもう一度会いたい
There's nothing I want to say, I just want to see you once more.
言いたいこと言えない根性無しかもしれない
Maybe I'm just a coward who can't say what I want.
それでいいけど
But that's fine.
僕の世界消えるまで
Until my world fades away,
会えぬなら
if I can't meet you,
君の側で眠らせて
let me sleep by your side,
どんな場所でも結構
any place is fine.
Beautiful world
儚く過ぎて行く日々の中で
In the fleeting days passing by,
Beautiful boy
気分のムラは仕方ないね
mood swings can't be helped, right?
Beautiful world
Beautiful boy
It's only love
もしも願い一つだけ叶うなら
If I am granted only one wish,
叶うなら
if it could come true,
君の側で眠らせて
let me sleep by your side.
Beautiful world
It's only love
Beautiful boy
Beautiful world
It's only love
Beautiful boy
ここは中空の庭
This is the mid-air garden,
空知らぬ雨で満ちゆく場所
a place filling with rain from an unknown sky.
世界がどんなに美しくても
No matter how beautiful the world is,
絶えず悲しみは降る
sorrow endlessly falls.
願う度に羽は濡れ
Each time I wish, my wings grow wet,
地上へと近づくの
drawing closer to the ground.
重い羽を閉じて そっとからだを包む
Closing my heavy wings, I gently wrap myself.
ここは中空の庭
This is the mid-air garden,
涙が雨に還る場所
a place where tears return to rain.
時には温度を奪われて
Sometimes losing my warmth,
時には汚れた羽を濯いで
sometimes rinsing my soiled wings,
やがて知るの
I come to know at last...
こんなにも強く
how strongly
明日を望めること
I can hope for tomorrow,
天泣が世界中に反射する
as sunshowers reflect across the world.
願いごとが叶う度
Each time a wish is granted,
堪らなく寂しいの
I feel unbearably lonely,
次の願いに会える保証なんてないから
for there is no guarantee I'll meet the next wish.
願う度に羽は濡れ
Each time I wish, my wings grow wet,
地上へと近づくの
drawing closer to the ground.
罪を抱え羽を閉じて
Embracing my sins and closing my wings,
いつか満ちる雨に溺れ
drowning in the ever-filling rain.
声が泡へと変わっても
Even if my voice turns to bubbles,
映る水面は光が差して
light shines upon the reflecting surface of the water,
私を照らす
and illuminates me.
ここは空にいちばん近い
This place is closest to the sky...
This place closest to the sky,
雲の頂きだからね
is the top of the clouds, you see.
はい！お聴きいただいたのはワンラスとキス、ビューティフルワールドのメドレー、
Yes! What you just heard was a medley of "One Last Kiss" and "Beautiful World,"
そして昨日リリースされました、天音かなたサードシングル、中空の庭でした！
and my 3rd single released yesterday, "Chukuu no Niwa"!
えー、しっとりめの三曲だったけど、どうだったかな？コメントもありがと！
Um, they were three emotional songs, how was it? Thanks for the comments too!
え、メンバー限定の配信でね、エヴァンゲリオンの映画をみんなと同時視聴しまして、
Um, in a member-only stream, we watched the Evangelion movie together,
その後歌枠で歌わせていただいたワンラスとキス、ビューティフルワールドを、みんながたくさん褒めてくれたので、
and everyone praised the singing of "One Last Kiss" and "Beautiful World" in my singing stream so much,
え、自己肯定感が爆上がりして、ライブでも歌ってしまいました。
that my self-confidence skyrocketed, and I ended up singing them at the live too.
え、美術館の中を歩いているように見せる演出っていうのをね、ずっとやってみたかったので、生で実現できて、スタッフさんやクリエイターさん本当にありがとうございます。
Um, I'd always wanted to do a staging where it looks like walking through an art museum, so being able to make it happen live—huge thanks to the staff and creators!
そしてそして、中空の庭はいかがだったでしょうか？
And, and how did you like "Chukuu no Niwa"?
え、昨日のね、夜0時にリリースされた新曲で、初めて聴いた人もすごく多いと思います。
Um, it's a new song released last night at midnight, so I think many of you are hearing it for the first time.
え、曲はフィギュアスケートの『ユーリ!!! on ICE』のエンディングの「History Maker」などを、
Um, the song—like the ending theme "History Maker" from the figure skating anime "Yuri!!! on ICE"—
作曲されているDEAN FUJIOKAさん、そして作詞を僕が、世界で一番大好きなボーカル、やなぎなぎさんにお願いしました！
I asked DEAN FUJIOKA, who composed it, and Yanagi Nagi, my absolute favorite vocalist in the world, to write the lyrics!
もうねタイムリープして数年前の自分に、こんな夢のような経験ができているというのを教えてあげたいと思うぐらい感激しています。
I'm so moved that I want to time leap and tell my self from a few years ago that I'd get to experience such a dream-like thing.
もうこれもね、それも今年もいつも側にいてくれるみんなのおかげです。本当に本当にありがと！
And this is all thanks to everyone who is always by my side. Thank you so, so much!
さあ、いよいよライブもラストスパートで、歌って踊るかなたそをその目に焼き付けて、もっともっと大好きになってね！かなたんしか勝たん！
Now, the live is finally in its final stretch! Burn dancing & singing Kanatasu into your eyes and grow to love me even more! Kanatan is the best!
よし、それでは、ずっと踊りたかったあの曲、必死で必死で覚えました。心を込めて踊ります。星の系さんで、恋。
Alright, then... that song I've always wanted to dance to, I learned it with all my might. I'll dance with all my heart. To "Koi" by Hoshino Gen.
恋 作詞・作曲：星野源
[Song: Koi - Lyrics & Music: Gen Hoshino]
営みの街が暮れたら色めき
When the bustling town grows dark and colorful,
風たちは運ぶわ カラスと人々の群れ
the winds carry crows and throngs of people.
意味なんかないさ 暮らしがあるだけ
There's no special meaning, just everyday life.
ただ腹を空かせて 君の元へ帰るんだ
Just emptying my stomach, I return to your side.
物心ついたらふと 見上げて思うことが
When I come to my senses, I suddenly look up and think:
この世にいる誰も 二人から
Everyone in this world started from two people.
胸の中にあるもの いつか見えなくなるもの
What's in our hearts, what one day becomes invisible—
それは側にあること いつも思い出して
always remember that it is right beside you.
君の中にあるもの 距離の中にある鼓動
What's inside you, the heartbeat within the distance—
恋をしたの貴方の 指の混ざり 頬の香り
I fell in love with you: the tangle of your fingers, the scent of your cheeks.
夫婦を超えてゆけ
Go beyond being a married couple,
ずっと ずっと...
Always, always...
みにくいと 秘めた想いは色づき
Unseen and hidden feelings take on color.
白鳥は運ぶわ 当たり前を変えながら
Swans carry them, changing what is taken for granted.
恋せずにいられないな 似た顔も虚構にも
I can't help falling in love, even with familiar faces or fiction.
愛が生まれるのは一人から
Love is born from a single person.
胸の中にあるもの いつか見えなくなるもの
What's in our hearts, what one day becomes invisible—
それは側にあること いつも思い出して
always remember that it is right beside you.
君の中にあるもの 距離の中にある鼓動
What's inside you, the heartbeat within the distance—
恋をしたの貴方の 指の混ざり 頬の香り
I fell in love with you: the tangle of your fingers, the scent of your cheeks.
夫婦を超えてゆけ
Go beyond being a married couple,
泣き顔も 黙る夜も 揺れる笑顔も
Tearful faces, silent nights, and swaying smiles,
いつまでも いつまでも
forever and ever.
胸の中にあるもの いつか見えなくなるもの
Things inside the chest, things that will someday fade from sight,
それは側にいること いつも思い出して
remember that it always means being by your side.
君の中にあるもの 距離の中にある鼓動
Things inside you, the heartbeat within the distance,
恋をしたの貴方の 指の混ざり 頬の香り
I fell in love with you—your intertwined fingers, the scent of your cheeks.
夫婦を超えてゆけ
Go beyond being a couple,
二人を超えてゆけ
go beyond just the two of us,
一人を超えてゆけ
go beyond being alone.
ライブもいよいよ終盤なんですが！
The live is finally reaching its climax!
みんなまだまだまだまだ盛り上がっていけるよなー！
Everyone, can you still get even more hyped?!
なぬっ!? ビシッ おリゃっ! バシッ
What?! Snap! Take this! Bam!
ツッコミも冴えて 本日快晴
My retorts are sharp, and today is clear skies.
さわっ ボロっ… ぎゅむっ パキッ
Rustle, tattered... squeeze, snap.
手にする全部 It's mine! くれくれって
Everything I get my hands on—'It's mine! Give it here!'
適度にかんばろっか そなんたっていいけどさ
Let's try our best moderately, though that's fine too.
必死にがんばろっか (そうだ!)
Let's work desperately hard (That's right!).
それが僕らしいよな
That's just like me, isn't it?
ダサすぎじゃねえんだわ! そんで貧ぼっちぃじゃねえんだわ!
It's not uncool! And it's not pathetic!
うん! 万事がバッチリイケてるに決まってる!
Yeah! Everything's bound to be going totally great!
(are you?) かなたちゃん☆!
(Are you?) Kanata-chan☆!
どどん! 前進上等! ちゃんと歓迎して
Boom! Advance is top-notch! Welcome me properly.
(wonder-la-der-la) 高まれ
(Wonder-la-der-la) Rise higher,
海空創造 ちゃんと驚嘆して
Create oceans and skies, and be truly amazed.
僕が言うんだもん 本当にするんだもん
Because what I say, I'll make it come true.
現実超えろ未来 あー!
Surpass reality, future, ah!
弱点も平気 スイッチでランチャー!
Weaknesses are fine, launch with a switch!
すなわち特者生存ワンダランDAんだってばいい
In other words, Fated Survivors' Wonderland DA...
(wonder-la-der-la) 楽しもう
(wonder-la-der-la) Let's enjoy it.
面白がれること探したまえ、over?
Search for things you can find funny, over?
返事聞かせてくれ!
Let me hear your reply!
右左なんかじゃない (かなたあーん!)
It's not about right or left (Kanata-aan!)
決めつけて一直線 (かなたあーん!)
Commit and go straight ahead (Kanata-aan!)
つまり企んだら発射オーライだ
In other words, once you plot it, launch is all right!
ワクワクすんぜ! しゃー!
I'm getting excited! Yeah!
初見の皆さん、あまねかなたは裏切らない！
To everyone watching for the first time, Amane Kanata will never betray you!
歌も配信も頑張るからまた遊びに来てね！
I'll work hard at both singing and streaming, so come hang out again!
いつも見てくれるへ民のみな…
To all the Hemins who always watch...
大好き！
I love you!
「何だよそんなこと言っちゃダメだ、おばか！」 「わ～すごい！ありがちょ～」
('What are you saying such things, you dummy!') ('Wow~ amazing! Thanks so much~')
日々これ騒祭で so my way!
Every day is a noisy festival, so my way!
虎視眈々でいたいんだもん
I want to remain vigilant and ready.
全方位にがっつりアンテナ張っていなくちゃ!
Got to keep my antennas fully up in all directions!
いつでも心はちゃんと純粋で (wonder-la-der-la)
My heart is always pure and true (wonder-la-der-la)
いいたいな 好奇心は絶えず熱気で
I want to say: my curiosity is always fueled by passion,
(wonder-la-der-la) 言いたいなって
(wonder-la-der-la) I want to say that.
言い聞かせるんだ 調子に乗ったら
I tell myself: if I get too carried away,
すぐ飽きられちゃうからあー!
people will get tired of me right away, ah!
タイトロープもどんとこいぜ (wonder-la-der-la)
Bring on the tightrope walk too (wonder-la-der-la)
すなわち特者生存ワンダランDAY (wonder-la-der-la) しがみつけ
In other words, Fated Survivors' Wonderland DAY (wonder-la-der-la) hold on tight!
“努力とは最後まで諦めないこと” メモっておいて!
'Effort means never giving up until the very end' — make a note of that!
ホントはbaby 自信なんかないよ
Truth is, baby, I have no confidence at all.
ホントはbaby 不安ばっかで泣きそうだ
Truth is, baby, I'm so full of anxiety I could cry.
でもねbaby 挫けないって決めたの
But you know, baby, I decided I won't be defeated.
だからbaby 挑戦したいよ 未開の天地 無限のフィールドで!
So baby, I want to challenge myself in unchartered realms, on an infinite field!
きた!
Here it comes!
ラスト行くぞー！
Last go!
前進上等！ちゃんと歓迎して
Advancement is top priority! Welcome me properly,
(wonder-la-der-la) 高まれ
(wonder-la-der-la) Let it rise higher,
海空創造 ちゃんと驚嘆して
Creating seas and skies, be amazed properly,
(wonder-la-der-la) 興奮しようよ
(wonder-la-der-la) Let's get excited!
僕が言うんだもん 本当にするんだもん
What I say becomes reality, because I make it happen!
現実超える未来 あー！
A future surpassing reality—ah!
弱点も平気 スイッチでランチャー！
Even weaknesses are fine, launcher on switch!
すなわち特者生存ワンダラダDAY
In other words, survival of the fittest Wander-la-der DAY!
(wonder-la-der-la) 楽しもう
(wonder-la-der-la) Let's enjoy it!
面白がれること探し放題でっせ
You can search all you want for fun things to do!
無限のフィールドで パニングしなくたっていい
In an infinite field, panning isn't even necessary,
ど真ん中一直線
Straight down the middle!
つまりこれが僕の答えなんだ
In short, this is my answer!
胸を張れ！今を生きるその意味を
Puff out your chest! The meaning of living right now—
明くる日も明くる来る日も確かめ進め！
Confirm it day after day and keep moving forward!
おりゃー！
Take this!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
やんないんじゃない、できないんだ！ドヤッ！
It's not that I won't do it, I can't! Ha!
ラスト贅沢で盛り上がっていくぞー！
Let's get hyped with the ultimate luxury!
あー近頃 巷で噂のダメ天使
Ah, lately I'm the useless angel rumored on the streets,
ダメなとこはもう天使のパワーでおぎなっていく
All my flaws will be made up for by angel power,
その予定さ！
or so is the plan!
ねえ 足りないの もっともっとあなたに気にしてほしい
Hey, it's not enough! I want you to pay more attention to me,
だけど注目されすぎたらビビる ディスコミュ系
But if I get too much attention, I panic—a socially awkward type!
天使のリングの点滅は 切れかけてるけど
My angel ring's halo is blinking and about to die out, but
見方を変えればこれも アイデンティティさ
If you look at it another way, even this is my identity!
なんて強がりさ 本当は曖昧な愛の感情も
Such bravado—truly, even my vague feelings of love
あなたと探したいの
I want to search for them with you!
ダメ ダメ ダメダメなあたしを もっと愛してね (YES!)
Love me even more, useless, useless me! (YES!)
大歓声のショットに無気力なエンジェル
A lifeless angel in the middle of roaring cheers,
天使ですが ドキドキ ドキドキをあげるよ
I may be an angel, but I'll give you heart-pounding thrills!
もっとあなたには ちゃんと見ていてくれるなら (エンジェル！)
If you'll keep watching me closely enough... (Angel!)
やるよ多分 ダダダダ ダメ天使は
I'll do it, probably! Da-da-da-da useless angel,
だ、だ、だ、駄目ですか？
is, is, is that bad?
だとしてもあたしは いいか？
Even so, is I okay?
やんないんじゃない できないんだ ドヤッ！
It's not that I won't do it, I can't! Ha!
テストで良い点とりたーい でも頭がちっとも追いつかなーい
I want to get good scores on tests—but my brain just can't keep up!
日曜日だって早起きしたーい 深夜のストゲがやめられない
I want to wake up early on Sundays—but I can't stop late-night games!
やる気がないとかそんなんじゃないんだ やる気があってもできないししょうがないなんて許してよ
It's not a lack of motivation! Even if I have it, I can't do it, so forgive me!
エンジェルリングをほばりながら こんなあたしに誰がしたんだか
Chomping on my angel ring, who made me into this kind of person?
天使の翼は使ってない 飛ぶのが怖いから
I don't use my angel wings because I'm scared of flying!
「本気をだしたら飛べますか？」みたいな顔はしている
With a face that says, 'Can you fly if you get serious?'
そんなハリボテの裏側に 隠した愛の感情が あなたに笑ってほしいのさ
The hidden love behind that papier-mâché wants you to smile at me!
ねえ ダメ ダメ ダメダメなあたしで いいですか？ 実際は一切の自信もないような 天使ですが
Hey, is it okay if I'm useless? Even though I'm an angel with zero confidence,
クル クル クルクルと巡る頭の中では あなたのことばかり考えてるんだ！
Inside my head spinning round and round, I'm only thinking about you!
ダメ ダメ ダメダメなあたしを もっと愛してよ
Love me even more, useless, useless me!
もらった愛で飛び立つ想いよ (エンジェル) 天使だから
My feelings ready to take off with love— (Angel) Because I'm an angel,
ドキドキ ドキドキをあげるよ もっとあなたには もっと好きになってくれるなら (エンジェル)
I'll give you heart-pounding thrills! If you'll come to love me even more (Angel)
やるよ多分 ダダダダ ダメ天使は
I'll do it, probably! Da-da-da-da useless angel,
だ、だ、だ、駄目ですか？
is, is, is that bad?
だとしてもあたしは いいか？
Even so, is I okay?
やんないんじゃない できないんだ ドヤッ！
It's not that I won't do it, I can't! Ha!
いや でも 努力はします ドヤッ！
Well, but, I'll try my best! Ha!
Thank you!
あー近頃街で噂のダメ天使
...
みんなライブ見てくれてありがとう！
Thank you everyone for watching the live!
天音かなた2022年誕生日記念グッズ、今年はすごいんです！
Amane Kanata's 2022 Birthday Commemoration Goods are amazing this year!
おしおママ描き下ろしの抱き枕カバー、
First, the Dakimakura cover illustrated by oshio-san,
そしてさとうぽいせんせい描き下ろしのフェイスタオル、そしてステッカー！
and the face towel and sticker illustrated by satou poi!
そしてそしてみんなが前々の配信で欲しいって言ってた、天使の輪クッション！
And what everyone kept asking for in streams, the Halo Cushion!
記念ボイスに関しましては今回は塩対応でクールな天音かなたボイスになっております！
As for the birthday voice, it's a cool Amane Kanata salt-response ASMR voice!
ダイムの皆さまはっていらしてくださいませ！
Daimu's everyone, please come visit us!
そしてそしてフルセット購入特典は、天音かなた直筆サイン入りポストカード！
And for the full set purchase bonus, it's an Amane Kanata digitally signed postcard!
今回はなんと数量限定ではなく無制限にてお届けしますので、欲しいと待ってくださるみんなに届くと思います！
This time, it's not quantity-limited, but made-to-order, so it will reach everyone who wants one!
今回も本当にライブありがとうございました！この後はアンコール、
Thank you all so much for the stream today! After this is the encore...
歌ってみたプレミア公開、PHONY！
and the premiere cover of "Phony"!
そして大ニュース！天音かなたついにフィギュアになります！
And finally, big news! Amane Kanata is finally getting a scale figure!
続報はこのあとTwitterにて！
The latest info will be on Twitter after this!
それではPHONYの応援、レッツゴー！
So let's go support "Phony"! Let's go!